Ahmed Elshafie CCIE#65074

Mob: 00966-541623198

Email: amwabw@hotmail.com



A Sr. Network Security Engineer with 8 years of experience. Completed projects in SD-WAN, Global MPLS and Security domains, on both LAN/WAN sides. Experienced designer and troubleshooter, eager and fast learner who speaks French, Fluent in English and Arabic is my native.

Personal Information:

Male, Sudanese.

DOB: 7th of November 1988

Visa Status: Valid and Transferable Iqama

Qualification:

Universities:

- Master Degree in Computer Science (Security major), 2015. University of Khartoum.
- Bachelor Degree in Computer Science, 2010.
 Sudan University of Science and Technology.

Valid Certificates:

- CCIE R&S #65074
- CCNP R&S
- CCNP Security
- CCDP

PCNSE

- CCNA R&S
- CCNA Security
- CCDA

Previous Experience:

King Abdulaziz International Airport (Sr. Network Security Engineer), Saudi Arabia Since 11/2020

- Cisco Firewalls administration and operation through FMC and ASDM.
- Fortinet Firewalls and Forti Analyzer management and operation.

- Network access control and guest services through Cisco ISE and Aruba Clear Pass.
- WSA proxy management.
- Participate in recommending, implementing security solutions.
- Handling escalations to vendors for critical security issues.
- Compliance with national and international security regulatories and authorities.

Nour Net (Sr. Network Engineer), Saudi Arabia 4/2016 - 4/2020

- MPLS Back-hauls management and activation (L2VPN, L3VPN).
- Configuration and management of P, PE and CE routers from scratch.
- Configuration of complex routing protocols (BGP, OSPF, EIGRP, RIP).
- Traffic engineering using QoS, PBR and BGP attributes.
- Layer 2 technology configuration and troubleshooting (STP, MST)
- SD-WAN configuration and installation (vSmart, vBond, vManage, vEdge)
- Configuration of customer firewalls.
- Implementing network security
- Network monitoring tools (Solar winds, Cacti).
- Managing and configuring VoIP Polycom products.

Ministry of Education (Network Engineer), Saudi Arabia 6/2012 - 5/2013

- Operating and managing the Datacenter.
- Network design and implementation including cabling and configuration.
- Installing wireless access points and connecting them to the infrastructure.
- Operating the voice network using Avaya systems and Cisco.
- Configuration of Security infrastructure, firewalls, VPN's, and surveillance systems.

Science Application (IT Engineer), Saudi Arabia 11/2010 - 5/2012

- Staff training on how to use the systems in their respective field.
- Providing support and troubleshoot network problems.
- Maintenance of the computer systems including software and hardware.
- Preparing cost estimation reports of required devices and software licenses.

Skills:

Continuous Learner.

Problem Solver.

Motivated

Detail Oriented

• Out of Box Thinker

Team Member

Cisco ISE

Firewalls

• IPS/IDS

FMC/ASDM

Web Security

• Linux

SD-WAN

Routing and Switch

MPLS/GMPLS

Windows Server

• DHCP, DNS, WDS Servers

FTP, SFTP, SCP

• SNMP, Netflow, Syslog

Microsoft Office & Visio